{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "If the size of the gate is 9feet*9feet and it has to be opened in exact 12 sec, and diameter of the shaft used is 3cm. Calculate the speed of rotation of the shaft.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "450 rpm",
        "b": "2400rpm",
        "c": "900 rpm",
        "d": "1600rpm"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "_______ is a kind of switch, which is ________ or ________ the moment we press or depress it. ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "LED, ON, OFF",
        "b": "Push button, activated, deactivated",
        "c": "Both LED, ON, OFF and Push button, activated, deactivated",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Limit switches are commonly used for",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Turning OFF of the light, when the refrigerator door is closed",
        "b": "Switching ON of car's dome lights when we open the door",
        "c": "Stopping of the washing machine when load becomes unbalanced",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "___________ is a device, that uses __________ and __________  to provide speed and torque conversions from a rotating power source to another device.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Gear box, lever, pulley",
        "b": "Gear box, shaft, pulley",
        "c": "Gear box, gear, gear trains",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "If the mass of the garage shutter is 500kg, and the diameter of the shaft used to pull is 9.6cm. Calculate the torque required to pull the garage shutter? Assume g=10m/s2.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "300N-m",
        "b": "270N-m",
        "c": "240N-m",
        "d": "180N-m"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A proximity switch can be",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Magnetic",
        "b": "Infrared",
        "c": "Both Magnetic and infrared",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "If the size of the gate is 12feet*12feet and it has to be opened in exact 10 sec, and diameter of the shaft used is 2.4cm. Calculate the speed of rotation of the shaft.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2100 rpm",
        "b": "900 rpm",
        "c": "2400rpm",
        "d": "1600rpm"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "If the diameter of the shaft used to pull the garage shutter is 2.4cm and the size of the garage shutter is 12feet*12 feet, rotation of the shaft is 500rpm. Then calculate the time required by the garage shutter to open completely from its completely closed condition.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "18 sec",
        "b": "9 sec",
        "c": "12 sec",
        "d": "7.2 sec"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "If the mass of the garage shutter is 300kg, and the diameter of the shaft used to pull is 2.4cm. Calculate the torque required to pull the garage shutter? Assume g=10m/s2",
      "answers": {
        "a": "30N-m",
        "b": "36N-m",
        "c": "42N-m",
        "d": "48N-m"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "<img src='images/garage/q1.gif' height='250' width='250' />The above figure represents a micro switch (limit switch), it has one normally open connection (N.O) and one normally closed connection (N.C). The connection between terminal1 and terminal2 is ________ and connection between terminal1 and terminal3 is _________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Normally open, normally closed",
        "b": "Normally closed, normally open",
        "c": "Normally closed, normally closed",
        "d": "Normally open, normally open"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "If the diameter of the shaft used to pull the garage shutter is 9.6cm and the size of the garage shutter is 15feet*12 feet, rotation of the shaft is 1000rpm. Then calculate the time required by the garage shutter to open completely from its completely closed condition.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "18 sec",
        "b": "21 sec",
        "c": "2.8 sec",
        "d": "7.2 sec"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question":"If the motor used for garage shutter opening and closing produces a torque of 7N-m and the torque required to pull the garage shutter is 14N-m.Calculate the required gear ratio.",
      "answers": {
            "a": "8:1",
            "b": "4:1",
            "c": "2:1",
            "d": "1:1"
          },
          "explanations": {
            "a": "",
            "b": "",
            "c": "",
            "d": ""
          },
          "correctAnswer": "c",
          "difficulty": ""
    }
  ]
}
